mba.com 2005-04-15

# Privacy Policy

The Graduate Management Admission Council® (GMAC®) is a licensee of the TRUSTe® Privacy Program. TRUSTe® is an independent, nonprofit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices.  This privacy statement covers the site [http://www.mba.com](http://www.mba.com/). Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users’ privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe®. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our legal department by email at [privacy@gmac.com](mailto:privacy@gmac.com).  If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or it is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe® through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process](http://www.truste.org/watchdog.html).  TRUSTe® will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns.   

Thank you for visiting mba.com, an Internet site developed and maintained by GMAC®. GMAC® is committed to honoring the privacy of the members of, and visitors to, our Web site.  Our privacy policy, as part of our overall Terms and Conditions, covers personally identifiable information you may share with us through mba.com.

Because protecting your privacy is important to us, you can be assured answers to the following questions:

  * What personal information does mba.com receive and how do we use it? 
  * Do you share my information with others? 
  * What is your opt-out policy? 
  * May I choose what information I disclose? 
  * May I choose what communications I receive from mba.com, GMAT® schools, and GMAC® strategic partners? 
  * What if I need to review or change the information I previously provided to you? 
  * What kind of security is used to protect my information? 
  * What about other institutions or companies featured on mba.com? 
  * What safeguards are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information? 
  * What about children's information? 
  * How will I be informed about changes to your privacy policy? 
  * Who can I contact if I have any questions regarding my privacy?

When you register for the Graduate Management Admission Test® (GMAT®) exam and other mba.com services, we may ask for your name, contact information, Social Security number, birth date, preferences, and certain demographic information.  This information allows us to provide you with access to our personalized services and communicate directly with you.  This information also allows us to verify that we are communicating with you and not someone else.  We use aggregated information about the use of our services to evaluate our users' preferences, improve our customer service, and enhance the user experience.  We may also use aggregated information to conduct research and for our publications.  This information is never attributed to individual users.

## Cookies

Like most Web sites, we use small bits of data called "cookies" stored on users' computers to simulate a continuous connection. Cookies let us "remember" information about your preferences and passwords and allow you to move within our Web site without reintroducing yourself. Cookies on the mba.com site are not used for marketing purposes and are not shared with any other parties without your permission.  Recent versions of Microsoft® Internet Explorer® and Netscape® browsers let you easily see and control cookies.  If you choose to block the use of cookies from our site, you may still use our site.  Your choice to do so will limit your user experience and access to functional site areas.

## Essay Insight

The Essay Insight® product enables your essays to be scored by e-rater®, an automated essay scoring technology developed at Educational Testing Service® (ETS®).  If you purchase the Essay Insight® product through the MBA Store® e-store on mba.com, your contact information and financial information will be passed on to Digital River, Inc., our mba.com store e-commerce services provider, in order to process your purchase.  (See "mba.com MBA Store®," described below).  Although the Essay Insight® server collects generic aggregate data about you, such as browser type, pages visited, and length of your session, this information is used only to evaluate areas of interest and to improve the Essay Insight® product.  With your permission, GMAC® may send you information about additional MBA preparation product offerings. 

## Graduate Management Admission Council (GMAC)

If you opt in when you are registering on mba.com, GMAC® may contact you to give you information about other GMAC® products and services related to graduate management education or to ask for your participation in market or other research conducted by or on behalf of GMAC®. See "Member Registration," described below.

## GMAT Registration

During GMAT® registration, you will be asked to provide your legal name, daytime telephone number, date of birth, and gender. These fields will be used to verify your identity as a GMAT® test taker. Failure to provide this information may result in an inability to process or delays in processing GMAT® registration and score reports or other administrative problems. It is important that you use your legal name as it appears on the identification you will use on test day. You will NOT be permitted to change this information after you have scheduled your test appointment. Educational Testing Service® (ETS®) administers the Graduate Management Admission Test® exam, and therefore collects your information when you register for the GMAT® exam. Registrant information is passed to ETS® only when you register to take the GMAT® exam through mba.com. At the time you register for the GMAT®, you are asked if you’d like schools to contact you with information about their MBA programs. If you choose to opt in and receive such information, the information you provide will be passed on to ETS®. GMAT® schools and certain strategic partners of GMAC® are then given access to a service called Graduate Management Admission Search Service® (GMASS®) that allows them to identify and recruit prospective students who meet specific criteria. The service provides schools with contact information (name, mailing address, and e-mail address ONLY) of registrants who meet the selection criteria that such organizations define. Should you have any questions regarding any of the GMAT® procedures and regulations, please contact a GMAT® customer service representative at ETS® by e-mail ([gmat@ets.org](mailto:gmat@ets.org)), telephone (1-609-771-7330) or fax (1-609-883-4349).

Data is passed to ETS® using an encryption technology called Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to keep your personal information safe. All of your personally identifiable, demographic, and background information is encrypted using a secure server for maximum security. Your information cannot be read as it travels to the ETS® server. See "What safeguards are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?" below for more information about data transmission security. 

## Log Files 

Like most standard Web-site servers, we use log files to collect system and security-related information.  This includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

## Member Profile

Users choose to provide mba.com with personally identifiable information. This information is used primarily to assist GMAC® in providing relevant member services and a secure, personalized user experience. If a user's personally identifiable information (e.g., zip code, phone, e-mail or postal address) changes, or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update, or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information.

## Member Registration

Personal information is collected on the mba.com registration form for several reasons, including: (i) personal identification and verification; (ii) to allow you to benefit from an array of GMAC® products and services; (iii) to allow us to contact you for customer service, if necessary; (iv) to customize the site content to meet your specific needs; and (v) to make application and service improvements to mba.com.  With your approval, members occasionally receive information on financial aid, recruiting events, enrollment preparation advice, and other noteworthy GMAC® news.  If at any time you no longer wish to receive such information, you can opt out. (See the "Opt-Out Policy," described below). 

## mba.com MBA Store

A user must provide contact information (e.g., name, e-mail, and shipping address) and financial information (e.g., credit card number and expiration date) to purchase products in the MBA Store® e-store. This contact and financial information is passed on to Digital River, Inc., our MBA Store® e-commerce services provider. This information is used for billing purposes and to a fill customer’s order. GMAC® does not store your credit card information. Each transaction is protected by the Digital River® Secure Sales Server technology (S3) along with Netscape® SSL encryption technology. 

## MBA Forums

The only requirement for attendance at the GMAC® sponsored MBA Forums® program is that attendee contact information provided during registration is shared with exhibiting business school institutions.  Regardless of whether registration was completed online or onsite, your contact information will be shared with exhibiting business school institutions.

## Privacy Exceptions

Although we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information as required by law in order to comply with a judicial or other governmental proceeding, court order, warrant or subpoena. Also, our privacy policy only applies to information you provide to us. We are not responsible for protecting information you provide to third parties.  Such third parties may have significantly different privacy policies from ours.

When you sign up on our site, you are given the option to allow GMAC® to collect and share your personal information with the entities referred to below in order to provide you with certain services. If you opt out of receiving such services during site sign up or at any other time, we do not (or will no longer) share your information with any outside entity (except as necessary to fulfill a transaction you have requested or unless you otherwise give us permission to do so).  GMAC® may also share your information in response to legal process, such as a court order or subpoena. 

If you register for the GMAT® exam and/or opt in to enable business schools to contact you or register as a member of mba.com and opt in to receive newsletters and other information, your information is shared with the entities listed below, as appropriate (such entities act as our agents in providing our services to you and agree to use your information only for that purpose). 

## Educational Testing Service (ETS)

Educational Testing Service® (ETS®) administers the Graduate Management Admission Test® (GMAT®) exam, and therefore collects your personal information when you register for the GMAT® exam. (If you sign up on mba.com, your personal information is passed to ETS® only if you also register to take the GMAT® exam through mba.com. Otherwise, your information is not shared with ETS®.) Data are passed to ETS® using an encryption technology called Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to keep your personal information safe. All of your personally identifiable, demographic, and background information is encrypted using a secure server for maximum security. Your personal information cannot be read as it travels to the ETS® server.

## Digital River, Inc.

Digital River, Inc. is our MBA Store® e-commerce services provider. If you purchase the Essay Insight® product through the mba.com MBA Store®, your contact information and financial information will be passed on to Digital River, Inc. in order to process your purchase. See "mba.com MBA Store" above.

## GMAT Using Business Schools

GMAT® using business schools are given access to a service, called Graduate Management Admission Search Service® (GMASS®), that allows them to identify and recruit prospective students who meet specific criteria. The service provides schools with contact information of GMAT® registrants who meet the selection criteria that schools define. You may opt in or opt out of participation in the GMASS® service during the GMAT® registration process. 

## Sallie Mae

GMAC® works with Sallie Mae® on its MBA LOANS® product as part of a strategic alliance. If you opt in to receive financial aid information, GMAC® will share your contact information with Sallie Mae® to enable you to receive such information.

At any time, you can unsubscribe to newsletters and other information through your member profile, available via the mba.com homepage. As a member, you may choose to occasionally receive e-mail updates from GMAC® (or GMAT® schools or GMAC® strategic partners) about MBA-related events in your area, special offers, and other noteworthy news items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Of course, if you would rather not receive them, please edit your member profile to opt-out. GMAC® reserves the right to limit membership options to those who do not wish to participate in its programs and offers. 

While we need certain information to register you as a unique user on mba.com to enable you to access personalized services, such as the MBA Pathfinder®  service, other requested information is optional and may be given at your discretion. 

We occasionally send out an e-mail newsletter to mba.com members to highlight features of the services we offer through mba.com. You can elect not to receive communications from us or from other parties, either when you register or by noting your preference in response to communications from us. To receive additional registration benefits, you may be asked to provide us more information. If you opt in, GMAT® schools may send you MBA program-related news and information.

We encourage mba.com members to update and edit their information. You can easily correct or update your information at any time via your member profile or other location specifically identified in connection with a particular service we offer.  (See the "GMAT Registration" subsection above regarding modification restrictions.) 

You may separately agree to provide your information to other institutions or companies who provide content for various parts of our services, in order to use their services, order their products, or receive offers from them. If you agree to provide information to these companies, that information will be subject to their privacy policies.

All sensitive information provided to mba.com is stored on managed servers and protected using a combination of security and access controls, including SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption for data transmissions.  SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send them to us. These data are accessed only for the purposes specified in this privacy statement. In addition, purchases made through the MBA Store® e-store are protected by the Digital River® Secure Sales Server technology (S3) along with Netscape® SSL encryption technology on every order transaction.  Credit card information is temporarily stored to complete transactions only. 

Our Web site does not target and is not intended to attract children under the age of 13. GMAC® does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. GMAC® intends to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a child we will make all reasonable efforts to delete that data from our records. For questions about children’s privacy or other issues at mba.com, please e-mail us at [privacy@gmac.com](mailto:privacy@gmac.com).

Any material changes to our privacy policy (including material changes in our use of personally identifiable information) will be noted on the home page of mba.com.

Please contact us directly at [privacy@gmac.com](mailto:privacy@gmac.com) with any questions or comments. For general information regarding privacy you can visit, the Better Business Bureau ([www.bbb.com](http://www.bbb.com/)) or the Federal Trade Commission ([www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)).

######   
Essay Insight®, GMAC®, GMASS®, GMAT®, Graduate Management Admission Council®, Graduate Management Admission Search Service®, Graduate Management Admission Test®, MBA Forums®, MBA Pathfinder®, and MBA Store® are registered trademarks of the Graduate Management Admission Council® (GMAC®). 

######   
Educational Testing Service®, E-rater®, and ETS® are registered trademarks of the Educational Testing Service®.

######   
MBA Loans® and Sallie Mae® are registered trademarks of Sallie Mae®. 

###### TRUSTe® and Click to Verify TRUSTe logo are registered trademarks of Trusted Universal Standards in Electronic Transactions.

###### Digital River® is a registered trademark of Digital River, Inc.

######   
Internet Explorer® and Microsoft® are registered trademarks of Microsoft Corporation®. 

######   
Netscape® is a registered trademark of Netscape Communications Corporation®.
